<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ML Tuts</title>
    <link>http://mltuts.online/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ML Tuts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:37:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mltuts.online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us 📞</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/menu/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:37:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/menu/contact/</guid>
      <description>Alex: E-mail: alex@mltuts.online
Jake: E-mail: jake@mltuts.online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us 👋</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/menu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:28:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/menu/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to ML Tuts! Our site is dedicated to providing high-quality tutorials and resources on machine learning, one of the most exciting and rapidly growing fields in technology today. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner looking to learn the basics of machine learning or an experienced data scientist looking to stay up-to-date on the latest developments, our team of experts has got you covered. Our tutorials cover a wide range of topics, including deep learning, natural language processing, computer vision, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 - Intro To Google Colab &amp; Working With Images</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/01-intro-to-google-colab-working-with-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/01-intro-to-google-colab-working-with-images/</guid>
      <description>Intro The default programming in Google Colab is Python System command for Python are written: !pip CTRP + ALT + P for opening code snippets Important Code Snippets Mounting Google Drive in your VM Downloading files to your local file system Open files from your local file system Showing CV2 Images Mounting gDrive And Opening Image From It # keep this modules in your notebook: from google.colab import drive from PIL import Image from matplotlib import pyplot as plt import cv2 # mount on google drive drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 - Working On Iris Dataset</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/02-working-on-iris-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/02-working-on-iris-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Intro Are you interested in learning how to use Python to analyze and visualize data? In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through the process of loading and manipulating the iris dataset, calculating mean, maximum and minimum values, and splitting the data into training and test sets. We&amp;rsquo;ll also show you how to display unique data and use visualizations, such as pie charts and graphs, to better understand the data. All the code in this post is written in Python, using modules like sklearn and matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
