<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ML Tuts</title>
    <link>http://mltuts.online/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ML Tuts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:37:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mltuts.online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us 📞</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/menu/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:37:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/menu/contact/</guid>
      <description>Alex: E-mail: alex@mltuts.online
Jake: E-mail: jake@mltuts.online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us 👋</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/menu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 15:28:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/menu/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to ML Tuts! Our site is dedicated to providing high-quality tutorials and resources on machine learning, one of the most exciting and rapidly growing fields in technology today. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner looking to learn the basics of machine learning or an experienced data scientist looking to stay up-to-date on the latest developments, our team of experts has got you covered. Our tutorials cover a wide range of topics, including deep learning, natural language processing, computer vision, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 - Intro To Google Colab &amp; Working With Images</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/01-intro-to-google-colab-working-with-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/01-intro-to-google-colab-working-with-images/</guid>
      <description>Intro The default programming in Google Colab is Python System command for Python are written: !pip CTRP + ALT + P for opening code snippets Important Code Snippets Mounting Google Drive in your VM Downloading files to your local file system Open files from your local file system Showing CV2 Images Mounting gDrive And Opening Image From It # keep this modules in your notebook: from google.colab import drive from PIL import Image from matplotlib import pyplot as plt import cv2 # mount on google drive drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 - Working On Iris Dataset</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/02-working-on-iris-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/02-working-on-iris-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Intro Are you interested in learning how to use Python to analyze and visualize data? In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through the process of loading and manipulating the iris dataset, calculating mean, maximum and minimum values, and splitting the data into training and test sets. We&amp;rsquo;ll also show you how to display unique data and use visualizations, such as pie charts and graphs, to better understand the data. All the code in this post is written in Python, using modules like sklearn and matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 - Exploring Olivetti Faces and Generating Numbers: A Data Analysis Journey</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/03-olivetti_faces-and-number-generating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/03-olivetti_faces-and-number-generating/</guid>
      <description>Intro In the world of data analysis, exploring diverse datasets and understanding their patterns and visual representations is crucial. In this blog post, we will embark on an exciting journey of analyzing the Olivetti Faces dataset, a collection of facial images, and delve into generating random numbers for further analysis. We will utilize Python and several powerful modules, such as sklearn, numpy, and matplotlib, to accomplish these tasks.
Olivetti Faces: Firstly, we will start by loading the Olivetti Faces dataset using the fetch_openml function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 - K-means Clustering</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/04-k-means-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/04-k-means-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Intro In unsupervised machine learning, clustering is a popular technique used to group similar data points. One of the most widely used clustering algorithms is K-means. K-means is a centroid-based clustering algorithm that partitions data points into k distinct clusters. In this blog post, we will explore the K-means algorithm and its implementation in Python using the scikit-learn and yellowbrick libraries. We will cover how to train the model, predict clusters, find centroids, and visualize the results using scatter plots, silhouette visualizations, and K-elbow methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 - K-means Clustering Pixels &amp; Hierarchy Clustering</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/05-k-means-clustering-pixels-hierarchy-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/05-k-means-clustering-pixels-hierarchy-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Intro In machine learning, clustering is a technique that involves grouping similar data points into groups or clusters. There are several clustering algorithms available, but in this blog post, we will explore two popular techniques: K-means Clustering and Hierarchical Clustering.
Important Code Snippets Mounting Google Drive in your VM Downloading files to your local file system Open files from your local file system Showing CV2 Images Used Modules import numpy as np from matplotlib import pyplot as plt from matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 - Linear Regression</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/06-linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/06-linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this blog post titled &amp;ldquo;06 - Linear Regression,&amp;rdquo; the author explores the concept of linear regression and how it can be applied to real-world data. The post begins by fetching a dataset and converting it from pandas to numpy. The author then selects the independent and dependent variables and converts them from imperial to metric units. Next, a scatter plot of the data is displayed, followed by the training of a linear regression model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 - K-Nearest Neighbours</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/07-k-nearest-neighbours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/07-k-nearest-neighbours/</guid>
      <description>Intro Are you interested in machine learning and classification? The K-Nearest Neighbours algorithm, or KNN for short, is a simple yet effective algorithm used for classification tasks. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into KNN&amp;rsquo;s implementation in Python, specifically in the scikit-learn library. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the necessary modules used, mounting Google Drive in our virtual machine, training and testing the model, calculating its accuracy, making predictions, interpreting confusion matrix values, and using other metrics such as precision and recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 - Logisitcal Regression</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/08-logisitcal-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/08-logisitcal-regression/</guid>
      <description>Intro Modules Used import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt from sklearn.datasets import fetch_openml from sklearn.model_selection import train_test_split from sklearn.linear_model import LogisticRegression from sklearn.metrics import classification_report from sklearn.metrics import confusion_matrix # za matricu konfuzije Load Mnist Dataset Version 1 And Displaying First Image With Number # load dataset dataset = fetch_openml(&amp;#39;mnist_784&amp;#39;, version = 1) # watchout to fetch correct version # dataset specs dataset.keys() # all what dataset holds dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 - Extras</title>
      <link>http://mltuts.online/ml/09-extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mltuts.online/ml/09-extras/</guid>
      <description>Examples of Clustering in Real Life Market Segmentation: Companies can use clustering techniques to group customers based on their purchasing behavior or preferences. By segmenting customers into different groups, companies can tailor their marketing strategies to target each group more effectively.
Image Segmentation: Clustering can be used in image processing to segment images into different regions based on similarities in color, texture, or other features. This can be useful in various applications, such as object recognition, medical imaging, and remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
